[Ikalgo] All I know is this,
you looked at a good-for-nothing
octopus like me,
and you said I was cool.
You even said
we could have been friends.
I can't stand by while you die!
I'm gonna save you!
Don't you die on me!
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in English]
[singer singing in Japanese]
POWER X AND X GAMES
[narrator] While Killua
was in the process
Gon was forming a bond as well,
with a Chimera Ant
who goes by the name Meleoron.
-[Meleoron] huh?
-The smoke will stick to your clothes,
and people
will smell you coming,
but honestly,
it doesn't really matter much.
While my invisibility
is sort of like my trademark,
my real ability
goes one step further.
What?
Here. I'll show you.
[inhales]
I can't sense him at all,
only the smell of cigarettes.
He's not here.
This is more than just invisibility.
without even making a sound?
That's impossible.
So how did he do it?
[gasps] Whoa!
Where did you come from?
Your mind simply refused
to acknowledge
It's like that, but more extreme.
Turning invisible really is just a decoy.
It helps me keep my true ability
a secret from everyone else.
[Gon]
Why tell me something so important?
[Meleoron]
Well, I've gotta earn your trust, don't I?
Yeah, it's kind of a risk,
but it's one I have to take.
See, if I can't get you to trust me,
then we won't be able to start anything.
Huh?
Like I said before,
we have to trust each other first.
Once you've agreed
to be my partner,
I'll be happy to tell you
everything you want to know.
What about your buddy?
Isn't he gonna have a fit
when he finds out
you teamed up
with a suspicious-looking monster?
[groans]
Why the hell am I
trashing myself like this?
It's not like I chose to be this way.
He sure is restless.
[Meleoron sighs]
I guess it doesn't matter.
Even a good friend
you've had for 20 years
could still stab you in the back.
Time is not a matter of trust.
You feel me?
[groans]
This deal is dead in the water.
Nah. It's fine.
I'll just insist on having it my way.
take down the King.
I'm taking revenge.
[Gon] Hmm.
[Meleoron sighs]
If you insist,
I guess I'll have to tell you.
What? Already?
[lighter flicks]
[gasps]
But at the time,
I didn't even realize
that someone who was
close to me had died.
Huh? Why not?
You just said you saw it happen.
Because I'd forgotten
who Peggy was to me.
I'd forgotten that he
was my foster father.
[dramatic music playing]
Memories of my human days
came flooding back.
my parents' names
and my own name,
bits of my childhood.
always carrying thick books
with him everywhere.
[Gon] Then, I think I get it now.
[Meleoron] Huh?
I think I'm finally starting to understand
why I felt I could trust you so quickly.
It's 'cause you seem so human,
Really? When I met you,
I had exactly the opposite reaction.
[Gon] Huh?
I could immediately sense
an inhuman beast
lurking deep within you.
That's why I wanted
to team up with you,
because we're not all
that different, you and I.
All right.
Let's get right to it, then.
Oh, right. I'm Gon Freecss.
I actually have one more ability,
and we just met
the condition to activate it.
[Gon gasps]
Time to show you my third ability.
[dramatic music playing]
Ha.
[bird chirping]
Wait a second.
Does that mean I was using
your Perfect Plan, too?
That's exactly right,
and the name of my third power
is God's Accomplice.
Now do you understand
how powerful this is?
This ability will allow us
to approach and attack
No matter how powerful
the King is,
one mega-punch to his
unguarded vitals, and he's done.
[Gon shudders]
[Meleoron] Hey, Gon,
you're just the perfect partner
I've been looking for.
If we work together,
we can deal that son of a bitch
an unprecedented blow.
back when you used
that Jan-Ken-Rock thing.
-Those were my men, you know.
-[gasps]
They're not my soldiers
or my allies anymore.
Well, I guess from their perspective,
I'm the one who changed, not them.
You know someone who'd be better?
[Gon] I sure do.
I'll contact him.
Hold on.
Right or wrong, I do trust you.
And I won't even regret my decision,
because I watched you,
and I spoke to you,
just because you trust them.
That's not how this is gonna work.
That make sense to you?
Mm-hmm. I get your point, but still--
Hey, it's my life
on the line here, right?
Listen. My Perfect Plan's
not invincible at all.
It's actually more vulnerable
than you might think.
as somebody with my ability,
what would they do then?
Hate to say it,
but when it comes to combat,
I'm the weakest
Chimera Ant around.
I'm basically a foot soldier.
Forget the King.
I couldn't even survive a punch
from a squadron leader.
If I just turn invisible,
I can be located with En.
It's already been tested,
so the other squadron leaders
know it, too.
I need my enemies to believe
that my power is weak.
They need to think
just a little bit of En
My point is that
I don't want to reveal my power
to anyone else,
not even if it's someone you trust.
You understand?
[Gon] Find out for yourself.
Huh?
I'll call him over,
but I won't mention that you're here.
-[cell phone beeps]
-[Meleoron] Hey, wait.
-You can watch things from a distance.
-[phone line ringing]
-Hi. It's--
-[Knuckle] Hey!
I've been waiting, idiot.
The boss had to make a move
because of you two kids.
The original plan's
been completely derailed,
but I approve of what
you're doing out there.
Uh…
[Knuckle] We can't just let five million
innocent people die like that.
The boss already used his ability
to surround the capital.
[Gon] really?
so they're not going to be able
to perform any kind
of long-distance sorting.
[Gon] Right.
[Knuckle] However, the boss and Mr. Knov
will be expending all their
energy to delay Neferpitou,
which means,
when the operation begins,
they're not gonna be in any condition
to take on the Royal Guards.
[sighs]
We fully expect
that more citizens
will gather in the capital
for the celebration.
There might still be a massacre.
The situation
hasn't gotten any less grim.
We can't contact
the chairman anymore.
He's focusing and honing
his energy somewhere,
[dramatic music playing]
The four of us
need to make a choice.
Do we summon reinforcements,
or face the three Royal Guards
all by ourselves?
[Gon] He's not here.
Are you saying
that you two split up?
Oh, I get it.
He was doing all this himself.
Can you call him?
We should all touch base real soon,
-and the sooner, the better.
-[Gon] Yeah.
We need to find
a halfway point for us
where we can meet up
when we can.
[Shoot] Mm.
[Knuckle] Here. Mandai City.
Right. Got it.
[hangs up]
[King] Checkmate.
Now, why didn't you concede defeat?
Uh…
[wincing]
[King] Do not make me repeat myself.
The match was decided
22 moves ago.
So then tell me
why you didn't concede.
Did you actually think
that I would make a mistake?
[gasping]
[yelps]
[King] The fool.
[dramatic music playing]
[man] Please, let me go!
What do you want?
Someone, anyone, help me!
[groans]
[man gasping]
[exclaims fearfully]
I'm just tired, that's all.
That's why I lost.
I might have a slight fever.
I'm really dizzy and weak.
Take eight hours and medicine.
I want you in top condition.
Lose again, and I won't be
interested in your excuses.
So rest like you mean it.
These games are quite difficult.
I'm shocked that it took you
less than half the time
it took to learn Shogi.
I just learned the trick to it.
That was all.
but every first-rate player
has a certain rhythm to his play.
The key is to disrupt their rhythm,
and therefore their game.
As soon as you learn the basics,
you can deduce their rhythm…
[dramatic music playing]
[King] …and once you know their rhythm,
disrupting it is easy.
A psychological approach
that would apply to any contest.
It's a board game
that they call Gungi.
and nearly all the citizens there
know how to play it.
However, pieces can be
stacked up to three high,
and the opening formation
of pieces is variable.
It requires
three-dimensional thinking,
making it somewhat different
from other board games
of this nature.
World tournaments have
been held around the globe
who is a five-time reigning champion.
Hmm.
So then if I defeat this champion,
I'll be the best in the world?
A fitting end to this diversion.
[cane tapping]
[narrator] Six days left
until the sorting.
A young girl appears
who will shape the fate of the King.
But in what way, exactly,
he has no idea at all.
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "Check and Mate."
-I'm Gon.
-[Killua] I'm Gillua.
-[Gon] Did you change your name?
-[Killua] What? No way.
[Gon] Say it again.
-[Killua] I'm Killua.
-[Gon] O.M.G.!
[singer singing in Japanese]